



I'm Archu SM

Software Developer

AGE 24

E-MAIL archusm007@gmail.com

PHONE +91 9526070220

EXPERIENCE 2 Years

Hello! I'm Archu SM. Software Developer specializing in backend web development and scripting. Experienced with all stages of the development including frontend, backend, MVC architecture like Django, Python and PHP shell scripting, SQL and No-SQL databases. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including JavaScript, SQL, No-SQL, Python, PHP. Strong background in testing and customer relations.

Professional Skills

Programing Languages Known

		52%
60%	C++	50%
75%	HTML	72%
85%	CSS	72%
<u>APIs</u>		
75%	Laravel (PHP)	50%
80%	Wx-Python	60%
75% 60%	Linux (Ubuntu >=12.x) Linux (CentOS >=7)	90%
75%	Google Big Query (SQL)	90%
75%		
90%	Scripting	90%
75%	Web Development Full-Stack or Backend	75%
	75% 85% APIs 75% 80% Experie 75% 60% 75% 75%	75% HTML 85% CSS APIs 75% Laravel (PHP) 80% Wx-Python Experience 75% Linux (Ubuntu >=12.x) 60% Linux (CentOS >=7) 75% Google Big Query (SQL) 75% 90% Scripting

75%

Research and Development

Projects Worked

Excpy

Excpy is an offer showing mobile app written in both android and IOS. I worked on the user event analytics reporting and recommendation engine - part which work as a core in the application. Used PHP, Mongo dB, Python and charting libraries like High Charts (written in JS and CSS) are used in the analytics reporting. And pure python job for the recommendation engine.

Client: Relocent Technologies Middle East

Phishing

Worked on a social engineering project for cyber security and created a phishing site for The bank based in Bahrain. As a part, to know the awareness on cyber-attacks in the bank.

Client: Cannot Reveal

Work Experience

2017 - Present

Rawdata Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

> Junior Django Developer

Working as a junior Django developer.

Started joining the company on April 3rd 2017.

2015 - 2017

Alephix Consulting
Pvt. Ltd.

Software Developer and Data Analyst

Developed Managed and tested web based analytics reports and analytics engines; basically written in python. Worked on database management in Big Query, MySQL and Mongo DB. Worked on cyber security projects like phishing.

Start Joined on 22nd June 2015 Resigned on 22nd March 2017

Education

2011 - 2015

B.Tech. Course completed in Computer Science & Engineering.

Cochin University of science and Technologies. (CUSAT)

Percentage of Marks: 60%

Basic School

SSLC

Board of Kerala

Percentage of Marks: 90%

2009 - 2011

Higher Secondary (12th)

Kerala State Higher Secondary Examinations

Percentage of Marks: 85%

My Interests

I have a keen interest in Artistic Painting. Interest in playing chess, I am a regular player and visitor in chess.com website. Reading books are my other hobbies and sometimes plays cricket.

Personal Details

Name	Archu S. M.
DOB	15-Apr-1994
Father's Name	Mr. V. Murali
Gender	Male
Nationality	Indian
Languages Known	English, Malayalam
Permanent address	Sulabhanivas, Valamangalam, South P.O. Thuravoor, Cherthala, Alappuzha, Kerala, India
Pin Code	688532
Contact No	+91 (0)9526070220
Email	archusm007@gmail.com